<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>SLAM/filter-vs-optim/opt-based on</title><link>https://salehahr.github.io/tags/SLAM/filter-vs-optim/opt-based/</link><description>Recent content in SLAM/filter-vs-optim/opt-based on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://salehahr.github.io/tags/SLAM/filter-vs-optim/opt-based/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Handling the computational complexity of optimisation-based SLAM</title><link>https://salehahr.github.io/studienarbeit/handling-the-computational-complexity-of-optimisation-based-slam/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://salehahr.github.io/studienarbeit/handling-the-computational-complexity-of-optimisation-based-slam/</guid><description>Parent: SLAM Index Source: Forster 2017 IMU Preintegration Complexity of nonlinear batch optimisation
The trajectory and the map, which comprise the states, grow with time The larger the SLAM problem, the less feasible it is to perform the optimisation in real-time Solutions to improve computational efficiency
Keyframe-based methods: discard frames except for a few selected keyframes Run the optimisation parallelly (e.g. tracking and mapping threads) Fixed-lag smoothing: Use of a local map of fixed size, with marginalisation of the old states (summarise the old states into a prior term) Filtering is a special case of this: window of size 1, i.</description></item><item><title>Some optimisation-based tightly-coupled multisensor SLAM algorithms</title><link>https://salehahr.github.io/studienarbeit/some-optimisation-based-tightly-coupled-multisensor-slam-algorithms/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://salehahr.github.io/studienarbeit/some-optimisation-based-tightly-coupled-multisensor-slam-algorithms/</guid><description>Parent: SLAM Index Source: [Wu 2018 Image-based camera localization: an overview](wu 2018-image-based-camera-localization_-an-overview.md)
Uses nonlinear optimization may potentially achieve higher accuracy due to the capability to limit linearization errors through repeated linearization of the inherently nonlinear problem
[117] Forster: preintegration theory [118] OKVIS: a novel approach to tightly integrate visual measurements with IMU optimise a joint nonlinear cost function that integrates an IMU error term with the landmark reprojection error in a fully probabilistic manner real-time operation: old states are marginalized to maintain a bounded-sized optimization window Li et al.</description></item></channel></rss>