<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>discussion/2020/2020-10 on Zettelkasten</title><link>https://salehahr.github.io/zettelkasten/tags/discussion/2020/2020-10/</link><description>Recent content in discussion/2020/2020-10 on Zettelkasten</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-uk</language><atom:link href="https://salehahr.github.io/zettelkasten/tags/discussion/2020/2020-10/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Thesis</title><link>https://salehahr.github.io/zettelkasten/thesis/thesis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://salehahr.github.io/zettelkasten/thesis/thesis/</guid><description>Introduction General Bladder cancer surgery — cryosection The navigation/localisation problem GRK diagnosis-bladder-cancer Problem statement Questions arising from the localisation task:
Which localisation algorithm do we use? We have settled on the camera-IMU combination. How do we take into account the non-constant calibration parameters between the camera and IMU (due to the surgeon&amp;rsquo;s manipulation of the cystoscope)? Also, modularity of setup: the calibration estimation allows the IMU-camera combination to be applied to different devices  Corresponding contributions Literature research deformable VI localisation Modelling the kinematic relations between the IMU and camera on the cystoscope Estimation of IMU calibration parameters for VI localisation on cystoscope Literature review (I) Monocular visual SLAM: problem: depth info, s.</description></item><item><title>DefOptimizer::DefPoseOptimization</title><link>https://salehahr.github.io/zettelkasten/studienarbeit/defoptimizer-defposeoptimization/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://salehahr.github.io/zettelkasten/studienarbeit/defoptimizer-defposeoptimization/</guid><description>Parent: DefTracking::Track As far as I understand it:
Uses g2o library for the optimisation (graph-based SLAM) cost function terms are converted to edges and nodes each cost function term seems to correspond to an edge in the graph in g2o paper/tutorial: an edge is fully characterised by its error function and its information matrix int DefPoseOptimization(Frame *pFrame, Map *mMap, double RegLap, double RegInex, double RegTemp, uint NeighboursLayers) // define optimiser, set solver optimizer = new &amp;hellip; optimizer.</description></item><item><title>Edges in g2o</title><link>https://salehahr.github.io/zettelkasten/studienarbeit/edges-in-g2o/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://salehahr.github.io/zettelkasten/studienarbeit/edges-in-g2o/</guid><description/></item><item><title>(Mur-Artal 2017) VI-ORB</title><link>https://salehahr.github.io/zettelkasten/bibliography/mur-artal-2017-vi-orb/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://salehahr.github.io/zettelkasten/bibliography/mur-artal-2017-vi-orb/</guid><description>URL: http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/abstract/document/7817784
Authors: Mur-Artal, Tardós
Code: http://paperswithcode.com/paper/visual-inertial-monocular-slam-with-map-reuse
Results (video): http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JXRCSovuxbA
Abstract current VI odometry approaches: drift accumulates due to lack of loop closure therefore there is a need for tightly-coupled VI-SLAM with loop closure and map reuse here: focus on monocular case, but applicable to other camera configurations builds on ORB-SLAM (from same author) IMU initialisation method (initialises: scale, gravity direction, velocities, gyroscope bias, accelerometer bias) depends on visual monocular initialisation (coupled initialisation) Other works: recent tightly-coupled VIO (both filtering- and optimisation-based) lack loop closure, so drift accumulates</description></item><item><title>Works of possible interest</title><link>https://salehahr.github.io/zettelkasten/bibliography/works-of-possible-interest/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://salehahr.github.io/zettelkasten/bibliography/works-of-possible-interest/</guid><description>General SLAM Cadena 2016 &amp;ndash; Past, Present, and Future of SLAM durrant-whyte 2006 slam tutorial part i Prerequisites g2o paper - graph-based SLAM Existing SLAM algorithms MonoSLAM, works by Andrew Davison focusing on fusion instead of vision-only SLAM
Maplab (filtering-based) not looking at filtering-based algos
mentioned in the Chen 2018 Review of VI SLAM paper:
ORB-SLAM paper — ORB features VIORB implementation ORB-SLAM3 (improves on ORBSLAM, incl.</description></item></channel></rss>