<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>filters/ESKF on</title><link>https://salehahr.github.io/tags/filters/ESKF/</link><description>Recent content in filters/ESKF on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://salehahr.github.io/tags/filters/ESKF/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>50.4.2 Multiplicative quaternion filtering (MEKF)</title><link>https://salehahr.github.io/studienarbeit/50.4.2-multiplicative-quaternion-filtering-mekf/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://salehahr.github.io/studienarbeit/50.4.2-multiplicative-quaternion-filtering-mekf/</guid><description>See also: Which orientation parametrisation to choose? Source: Markley 2014 Main idea is to use
the quaternion as a global rotation representation
a three component state vector as the local representation of rotation errors each term (q_true, delta_q, q_est) is a normalised unit quaternion
Any of the rotation error representations can be used to calculate delta_theta, which is part of the error state of the MEKF.</description></item><item><title>50.7.2 Calculation of K and P in ESKF update</title><link>https://salehahr.github.io/studienarbeit/50.7.2-calculation-of-k-and-p-in-eskf-update/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://salehahr.github.io/studienarbeit/50.7.2-calculation-of-k-and-p-in-eskf-update/</guid><description>Parent: 50.3 Error-State Kalman Filter , eskf-update See also: Evaluation of the H Jacobian Source: Solà 2017 Quaternion kinematics for ESKF The filter correction equations are (yields a posteriori estimates)
Notes:
Here, the simplest form of the covariance update is used. This has poor numerical stability, however (no guarantee of symmetricity or positive definiteness) More stable forms are e.g. Joseph form (symmetric and positive) Error correction?</description></item><item><title>KF kinematics</title><link>https://salehahr.github.io/studienarbeit/kf-kinematics/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://salehahr.github.io/studienarbeit/kf-kinematics/</guid><description>Overview of KF states (true, nominal, error) Nominal state kinematics Error state kinematics Old stuff:</description></item><item><title>50.5.1.1 States of the ESKF for estimating IMU pose</title><link>https://salehahr.github.io/studienarbeit/50.5.1.1-states-of-the-eskf-for-estimating-imu-pose/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://salehahr.github.io/studienarbeit/50.5.1.1-states-of-the-eskf-for-estimating-imu-pose/</guid><description>Parent: IMU index Backlinks: Fusing IMU with complementary sensory data Source: Solà 2017 Quaternion kinematics for ESKF Full state Vector with 19 elements The corresponding kinematics equations/motion model is given in IMU kinematic equations/motion model .
Notes:
The angular error in 3D space is given by the notation. In quaternion space, this angle is halved, with  (&amp;lsquo;double cover&amp;rsquo;, s. [Unit quaternions](unit quaternions.md), rotation-error-representation )
The angular error is defined locally w.</description></item><item><title>50.7.1 Observation of the error state (filter correction)</title><link>https://salehahr.github.io/studienarbeit/50.7.1-observation-of-the-error-state-filter-correction/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://salehahr.github.io/studienarbeit/50.7.1-observation-of-the-error-state-filter-correction/</guid><description>Parents: [50.3 Error-State Kalman Filter](50.3 error-state kalman filter.md), [50.5 eskf update / fusing imu with complementary sensory data](50.5 eskf update _ fusing-imu-with-complementary-sensory-data.md) Source: Solà 2017 Quaternion kinematics for ESKF Given is a non-IMU sensor with the measurement function [ Solà , markley ] where x_t is the true state and v is a white Gaussian noise Source: Markley If the measurements are given in quaternion form:
we can directly calculate the orientation error between measured orientation and estimated orientation this becomes our &amp;lsquo;measured&amp;rsquo; angular error which can be used to calculate the residual term [JPL convention] q_meas x (q_est).</description></item><item><title>50.7.1.1 H Jacobian matrix in the ESKF filter correction</title><link>https://salehahr.github.io/studienarbeit/50.7.1.1-h-jacobian-matrix-in-the-eskf-filter-correction/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://salehahr.github.io/studienarbeit/50.7.1.1-h-jacobian-matrix-in-the-eskf-filter-correction/</guid><description>Parent: Filter correction , eskf-update Source: Solà 2017 Quaternion kinematics for ESKF Evaluation of the H Jacobian
In the prediction stage, the filter estimates the error state. Therefore, the Jacobian H needs to be defined w.r.t. the error state , and evaluated at the true state estimate  However, as the error state mean is zero (not yet observed), the true state is approximated to the nominal state  Thus we can use the nominal state as the evaluation point The first Jacobian Depends on the sensor&amp;rsquo;s particular measurement function The second Jacobian with Source: Markley 2014 Measurement sensitivity matrix (Jacobian w.</description></item><item><title>50.7.3 ESKF reset</title><link>https://salehahr.github.io/studienarbeit/50.7.3-eskf-reset/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://salehahr.github.io/studienarbeit/50.7.3-eskf-reset/</guid><description>Parent: Fusing IMU with complementary sensory data Backlinks: 50.3 Error-State Kalman Filter Source: Markley moves the rotation error to the global rotation this keeps the rotation error small and far from any singularities To update the global state, the reset has to obey The reset has to preserve the quaternion norm, therefore an exact unit norm expression must be used, instead of an approximation. Using the Rodrigues parameter , the reset becomes which leads to a two step update (1.</description></item></channel></rss>