<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>software/sockets on</title><link>https://salehahr.github.io/quartz/tags/software/sockets/</link><description>Recent content in software/sockets on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://salehahr.github.io/quartz/tags/software/sockets/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Sockets Errno 10054</title><link>https://salehahr.github.io/quartz/studienarbeit/sockets-errno-10054/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://salehahr.github.io/quartz/studienarbeit/sockets-errno-10054/</guid><description>Parent: SofaPython Index WSAECONNRESET 10054 Connection reset by peer. An existing connection was forcibly closed by the remote host. This normally results if the peer application on the remote host is suddenly stopped, the host is rebooted, the host or remote network interface is disabled, or the remote host uses a hard close (see setsockopt for more information on the SO_LINGER option on the remote socket). This error may also result if a connection was broken due to keep-alive activity detecting a failure while one or more operations are in progress.</description></item><item><title>Sending data using sockets</title><link>https://salehahr.github.io/quartz/studienarbeit/sending-data-using-sockets/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://salehahr.github.io/quartz/studienarbeit/sending-data-using-sockets/</guid><description>Parent: SofaPython Index http://github.com/psomers3/PyDataSocket
http://docs.python.org/3/howto/sockets.html Sockets: form of IPC (inter-process communication), for cross-platform communication (Alternatives, for fast IPC: pipes, shared memory)
“client” socket - an endpoint of a conversation e.g. browser, other client applications “server” socket, which is more like a switchboard operator. The client application (your browser, for example) uses e.g. web server (uses both server and client sockets) Roughly, how a socket works (ex: clicking a link on the browser) Client socket (browser) / Receive</description></item></channel></rss>