<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Chaos Theory Index on Zettelkasten</title><link>https://salehahr.github.io/zettelkasten/math/chaos/</link><description>Recent content in Chaos Theory Index on Zettelkasten</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-uk</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://salehahr.github.io/zettelkasten/math/chaos/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Chaos Theory Index</title><link>https://salehahr.github.io/zettelkasten/math/chaos/__index/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://salehahr.github.io/zettelkasten/math/chaos/__index/</guid><description> Introduction what-is-chaos-theory chaos-and-determinism sensitivity-to-initial-conditions</description></item><item><title/><link>https://salehahr.github.io/zettelkasten/math/chaos/chaos-and-determinism/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://salehahr.github.io/zettelkasten/math/chaos/chaos-and-determinism/</guid><description>Chaos and determinism One might think that chaotic systems might have nothing to do with deterministic systems.
Chaotic systems are described to be &amp;lsquo;unpredictable&amp;rsquo;. It is normally assumed that &amp;lsquo;deterministic = predictable&amp;rsquo;. However, in real life, the information/data of a natural system is never completely available—we don&amp;rsquo;t know everything about the system, there are modelling errors, etc.
This is at odds with the assumption that one makes when analysing deterministic systems: that all the data of the system is available.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://salehahr.github.io/zettelkasten/math/chaos/sensitivity-to-initial-conditions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://salehahr.github.io/zettelkasten/math/chaos/sensitivity-to-initial-conditions/</guid><description>Sensitivity to initial conditions Deterministic systems can exhibit chaotic behaviour if they are highly sensitive to initial conditons.
This sensitivity to initial conditions is the hallmark of a chaotic system.
Thus, if a system is described to be deterministic, but without 100% knowledge of the system parameters, this system may well be very unpredictable if it is also a chaotic deterministic system.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://salehahr.github.io/zettelkasten/math/chaos/what-is-chaos-theory/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://salehahr.github.io/zettelkasten/math/chaos/what-is-chaos-theory/</guid><description>What is chaos theory? A branch of mathematics that deals with nonlinear dynamical systems.
System: a set of interacting components that form a larger whole Nonlinear: the whole system is something greater than just the additions (superposition) of the effects of the individual parts, due to nonlinear relationships such as feedback multiplicative effects between components &amp;hellip; Dynamical: the system changes over time based on its current state Chaotic systems are a subset of nonlinear dynamical systems.</description></item></channel></rss>