<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Permanent notes on Zettelkasten</title><link>https://salehahr.github.io/zettelkasten/permanent/</link><description>Recent content in Permanent notes on Zettelkasten</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-uk</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://salehahr.github.io/zettelkasten/permanent/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Which orientation parametrisation to choose?</title><link>https://salehahr.github.io/zettelkasten/permanent/20.4-which-orientation-parametrisation-to-choose/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://salehahr.github.io/zettelkasten/permanent/20.4-which-orientation-parametrisation-to-choose/</guid><description>Source: MKok 2017 Estimation algorithms (filtering, smoothing) usually assume that the unknown states and parameters are represented in Euclidean space
Due to wrapping and gimbal lock, Euclidian addition and subtraction don&amp;rsquo;t work Also generally don&amp;rsquo;t work for rotation matrices and unit quaternions Constraints (unit quaternion norm, rotation matrix orthogonality) are usually hard to implement in estimation algorithms These concerns led to the development of the MEKF .
To deal with this: Linearisation of an orientation in SO(3) Alternative method to estimate orientation:</description></item><item><title>Endoscope</title><link>https://salehahr.github.io/zettelkasten/permanent/30.1.2-endoscope/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://salehahr.github.io/zettelkasten/permanent/30.1.2-endoscope/</guid><description>Source: NHS The general term for the medical instrument used to perform endoscopy is, correspondingly, the endoscope. It is a device that makes use of optical technology to relay images from one end of the scope to another.
Functions are  not only for looking inside, but also have additional functionalities such as removing small tissue samples (biopsy) Insertion either through
natural body orifices (e.g. mouth, urethra) small incision in case a keyhole surgery is being performed</description></item><item><title>Endoscopes</title><link>https://salehahr.github.io/zettelkasten/permanent/30-endoscopes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://salehahr.github.io/zettelkasten/permanent/30-endoscopes/</guid><description>Backlinks: Leiner Endoscopy and bladder cancery surgery
Procedure
Cystoscopy to inspect the bladder If tumour is found, do resection &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; cryosection Cancer detected &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; tumour removal Endoscopy Endoscopes (general) Types of endoscopes Endoscope system components Endoscope specification</description></item><item><title>Endoscopy</title><link>https://salehahr.github.io/zettelkasten/permanent/30.1.1-endoscopy/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://salehahr.github.io/zettelkasten/permanent/30.1.1-endoscopy/</guid><description>Source: NHS Backlinks: Endoscopes Endoscopy is a procedure which enables inspection of organs inside the body. The prefix &amp;lsquo;endo&amp;rsquo; comes from the Greek language and means &amp;lsquo;within&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;inside&amp;rsquo;, cf. the prefix &amp;lsquo;exo&amp;rsquo;/&amp;lsquo;ecto&amp;rsquo; meaning &amp;lsquo;outside&amp;rsquo;. Endo- from Greek ἔνδον (within, inside), cf. exo-/ecto- from έκτός (outside) The instrument: endoscope</description></item><item><title>Types of endoscopes</title><link>https://salehahr.github.io/zettelkasten/permanent/30.1.2.1-types-of-endoscopes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://salehahr.github.io/zettelkasten/permanent/30.1.2.1-types-of-endoscopes/</guid><description>Parent: Permanent notes Source: Leiner Digital Endoscope Design Backlinks: Endoscopes Types of endoscopes
Endoscopes can be classified according to their flexibility, thus resulting in &amp;lsquo;rigid&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;flexible&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;semi-rigid&amp;rsquo; variants.
Video sensor at distal (&amp;ldquo;away from the surgeon&amp;rdquo;, opposite of proximal) end allows rigid endoscope to be converted to a flexible one solely by mechanical design Note: the term endoscope in hospital environments typically refers to the flexible variant In rigid endoscopes, an array of rod lenses (lenses which are much longer than their diameter) within a metal tube — also known as a telescope — are used to transmit the images from the [distal end to the proximal end](distal end to the proximal end.</description></item><item><title>Monocular depth perception</title><link>https://salehahr.github.io/zettelkasten/permanent/10-monocular-depth-perception/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://salehahr.github.io/zettelkasten/permanent/10-monocular-depth-perception/</guid><description>Depth perception in real life In nature, prey animals typically have eyes on either side of their head to maximise field of view, while most predators have forward-facing eyes with overlapping fields of vision (binocular vision) for maximum depth perception. Humans also have binocular vision. (Some exceptions: fruit bats, killer whales)
We perceive depth, or distance to the objects that we see, based on several visual cues.</description></item></channel></rss>