<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Permanent notes on Zettelkasten</title><link>https://salehahr.github.io/zettelkasten/permanent/</link><description>Recent content in Permanent notes on Zettelkasten</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-uk</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://salehahr.github.io/zettelkasten/permanent/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>30.1.2.2 Endoscope system components</title><link>https://salehahr.github.io/zettelkasten/permanent/30.1.2.2-endoscope-system-components/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://salehahr.github.io/zettelkasten/permanent/30.1.2.2-endoscope-system-components/</guid><description>Source: Leiner Imaging system (rod lens array for rigid endoscopes) within a tube/shaft
Illumination/Light source (it&amp;rsquo;s dark inside the body)
separate from the imaging system in order to reduce glare [low contrast of received image] surrounds the imaging system like a ring light Video camera
Coupling device (camera to imaging system)
Sheath and bridge which contain the telescope, fibre optics, and provides a channel for other stuff like irrigation, forceps, other surgical instruments</description></item><item><title>30.1.2.3 Endoscope specification</title><link>https://salehahr.github.io/zettelkasten/permanent/30.1.2.3-endoscope-specification/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://salehahr.github.io/zettelkasten/permanent/30.1.2.3-endoscope-specification/</guid><description>Source: Leiner Field of view: maximum angle that can be viewed Leiner Generally constructed so that the FOV is wide enough so that the &amp;lsquo;head on&amp;rsquo; view is visible even when the DOV is not zero. Leiner This is to reduce the chances of bumping the instrument into anatomy right in front of the shaft. Leiner Direction of view: angular offset of the optical axis from the longitudinal axis of the endoscope shaft</description></item><item><title>Endoscope</title><link>https://salehahr.github.io/zettelkasten/permanent/30.1.2-endoscope/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://salehahr.github.io/zettelkasten/permanent/30.1.2-endoscope/</guid><description>Source: NHS The general term for the medical instrument used to perform endoscopy is, correspondingly, the endoscope. It is a device that makes use of optical technology to relay images from one end of the scope to another.
Functions not only for looking inside, but also have additional functionalities such as removing small tissue samples (biopsy) Insertion either through
natural body orifices (e.g. mouth, urethra) small incision in case a keyhole surgery is being performed Subtopics Types of endoscopes Components Specification</description></item><item><title>Endoscopes</title><link>https://salehahr.github.io/zettelkasten/permanent/30-endoscopes-index/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://salehahr.github.io/zettelkasten/permanent/30-endoscopes-index/</guid><description> Endoscopy Endoscopes (general) Types of endoscopes Endoscope system components Endoscope specification</description></item><item><title>Endoscopy</title><link>https://salehahr.github.io/zettelkasten/permanent/30.1.1-endoscopy/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://salehahr.github.io/zettelkasten/permanent/30.1.1-endoscopy/</guid><description>Source: NHS Backlinks: Endoscopes Endoscopy is a procedure which enables inspection of organs inside the body. The prefix &amp;lsquo;endo&amp;rsquo; comes from the Greek language and means &amp;lsquo;within&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;inside&amp;rsquo;, cf. the prefix &amp;lsquo;exo&amp;rsquo;/&amp;lsquo;ecto&amp;rsquo; meaning &amp;lsquo;outside&amp;rsquo;. Endo- from Greek ἔνδον (within, inside), cf. exo-/ecto- from έκτός (outside) The instrument: endoscope</description></item><item><title>Types of endoscopes</title><link>https://salehahr.github.io/zettelkasten/permanent/30.1.2.1-types-of-endoscopes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://salehahr.github.io/zettelkasten/permanent/30.1.2.1-types-of-endoscopes/</guid><description>Source: Leiner Endoscopes can be classified according to their flexibility, thus resulting in &amp;lsquo;rigid&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;flexible&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;semi-rigid&amp;rsquo; variants. Video sensor at distal (&amp;ldquo;away from the surgeon&amp;rdquo;, opposite of proximal) end allows rigid endoscope to be converted to a flexible one solely by mechanical design Note: the term endoscope in hospital environments typically refers to the flexible variant More specialised endoscopes may be referred to by specific names, such as the cystoscope (for scoping bladders).</description></item><item><title>Monocular depth perception</title><link>https://salehahr.github.io/zettelkasten/permanent/10-monocular-depth-perception/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://salehahr.github.io/zettelkasten/permanent/10-monocular-depth-perception/</guid><description>Depth perception in real life In nature, prey animals typically have eyes on either side of their head to maximise field of view, while most predators have forward-facing eyes with overlapping fields of vision (binocular vision) for maximum depth perception. Humans also have binocular vision. (Some exceptions: fruit bats, killer whales)
We perceive depth, or distance to the objects that we see, based on several visual cues.</description></item><item><title>50.1 Why Kalman filters?</title><link>https://salehahr.github.io/zettelkasten/permanent/50.1-why-kalman-filters/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://salehahr.github.io/zettelkasten/permanent/50.1-why-kalman-filters/</guid><description>Source: rlabbe We work with 2 sources of data:
Sensor measurements Our own predictions (based on knowledge of system behaviour) Sensors are noisy, don&amp;rsquo;t give perfect information
Simple solution: to average readings However, this doesn&amp;rsquo;t work when the sensor is too noisy data collection not possible The prediction, however, is also susceptible to noise (the world is noisy, outside/unaccounted for influences).
In short: &amp;ldquo;Knowledge is uncertain, and we [must] alter our beliefs based on the strength of the evidence.</description></item></channel></rss>