<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>-resources/-bibliography/bib-to-read on Zettelkasten</title><link>https://salehahr.github.io/zettelkasten/tags/resources/-bibliography/bib-to-read/</link><description>Recent content in -resources/-bibliography/bib-to-read on Zettelkasten</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-uk</language><atom:link href="https://salehahr.github.io/zettelkasten/tags/resources/-bibliography/bib-to-read/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Maley 2013 MEKF for Nonspinning Guided Projectiles</title><link>https://salehahr.github.io/zettelkasten/studienarbeit/maley-2013-mekf-for-nonspinning-guided-projectiles/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://salehahr.github.io/zettelkasten/studienarbeit/maley-2013-mekf-for-nonspinning-guided-projectiles/</guid><description>Source: http://apps.dtic.mil/sti/citations/ADA588831</description></item><item><title>Markley 2003 Attitude Error Representations for Kalman Filtering</title><link>https://salehahr.github.io/zettelkasten/studienarbeit/markley-2003-attitude-error-representations-for-kalman-filtering/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://salehahr.github.io/zettelkasten/studienarbeit/markley-2003-attitude-error-representations-for-kalman-filtering/</guid><description>Source: http://scholar.google.com/scholar?cluster=9266330323139560128&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;as_sdt=0,5 Author: FL Markley
Motivation
Quaternion as an attitude representation
Good: lowest dimensionality while being a globally nonsingular representation Not so good: must obey a unit norm constraint In research, various methods for either getting around the norm constraint, or to enforce it
Most successful method employs the global attitude as a unit quaternion with a 3-comp attitude error representation
MEKF doesn&amp;rsquo;t estimate the quaternion state.</description></item><item><title>Rotations / SO(3) group index</title><link>https://salehahr.github.io/zettelkasten/rotations/rotations-so3-group-index/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://salehahr.github.io/zettelkasten/rotations/rotations-so3-group-index/</guid><description>Group theory SE(3) Special Euclidian Group SO(3) 3D rotation group Lie group, Lie algebra Exponential map Logarithm map Ambiguities in rotation representations Active/passive or Alibi/alias rotation transformations Intrinsic vs extrinsic rotations Rotation representations Orientation parametrisations Rotation error representation Which orientation parametrisation to choose? Linearisation of an orientation in SO(3) As Euler angles Euler angles Rotations as xyz Bryan-Tait angles (Kardanwinkel) Axis/angle Euler axis/angle representation As quaternions Quaternion index Quaternion to rotation matrix Kinematics Kinematics primer Chaining rotation matrices and angular velocities IMU specific IMU preintegration on manifold To read https://rip94550.</description></item><item><title>Pizarro 2016 Schwarps</title><link>https://salehahr.github.io/zettelkasten/studienarbeit/pizarro-2016-schwarps/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://salehahr.github.io/zettelkasten/studienarbeit/pizarro-2016-schwarps/</guid><description>Author: Daniel Pizarro et al.
Abstract
Warp between two images of a deforming surface: a transformation that depict the geometric deformation between the two &amp;lsquo;maps points between images of a deforming surface&amp;rsquo; Current approach to enforce a warp&amp;rsquo;s smoothness: penalise its second order partial derivatives However this favours locally affine warps Does not capture the local projective component of the image deformation Propose: novel penalty to smooth the warp while capturing the deformation&amp;rsquo;s local projective structure Proposed penalty is based on equivalents to the Schwarzian derivatives Schwarzian derivatives: projective differential invariants exactly preserved by homographies Methodology to derive a set of PDEs with only homographies as the solutions Validation: Schwarps outperform existing warps in modeling and extrapolation power: perform better in deformable reconstruction methods Introduction/Related work</description></item><item><title>DBoW2 weighing and scoring</title><link>https://salehahr.github.io/zettelkasten/studienarbeit/dbow2-weighing-and-scoring/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://salehahr.github.io/zettelkasten/studienarbeit/dbow2-weighing-and-scoring/</guid><description>Source: http://github.com/dorian3d/DBow</description></item><item><title>Forster 2017 IMU Preintegration</title><link>https://salehahr.github.io/zettelkasten/studienarbeit/forster-2017-imu-preintegration/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://salehahr.github.io/zettelkasten/studienarbeit/forster-2017-imu-preintegration/</guid><description>Authors: Forster et al
Abstract:
First contribution: preintegration theory (building up on Lupton&amp;rsquo;s work) what&amp;rsquo;s different from Lupton&amp;rsquo;s: addresses manifold structure of the rotation group, analytic derivation of all Jacobians Lupton&amp;rsquo;s work uses Euler angles Using Euler angles and techniques of Euclidian spaces for state propagation/covariance estimation is not properly invariant under rigid transformations uncertainty propagation, a-posteriori bias correction same as Lupton: integration performed in local frame, eliminating need for reintegrating when linearisation point changes Second contribution: integration of the preintegrated IMU model into a visual-inertial pipeline The system presented uses incremental smoothing for fast computation of the optimal MAP estimate Uses structureless model (3D landmarks are not part of the variables to be estimated) for visual measurements &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; allows eliminating large numbers of variables Motivation:</description></item><item><title>Grisetti 2011 - Tutorial graph-based SLAM</title><link>https://salehahr.github.io/zettelkasten/studienarbeit/grisetti-2011/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://salehahr.github.io/zettelkasten/studienarbeit/grisetti-2011/</guid><description>temp
Backlinks: What is SLAM? Abstract
formulate SLAM using a graph nodes: poses of the robot (as well as landmark postiions) at different points in time edges: constraints between poses come from sensor measurements/observations robot movement/control input constraints can contradict each other, due to effect of noise in sensor readings solve the graph, i.e. compute the map: find the spatial configuration of the nodes that best satisfy the constraints/edges tutorial for back-end (optimisation) part of graph-based SLAM :: Navigation task: requires a map and knowledge of current position relative to locations in the map</description></item><item><title>Badias 2020 MORPH-DSLAM</title><link>https://salehahr.github.io/zettelkasten/studienarbeit/badias-2020-morph-dslam/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://salehahr.github.io/zettelkasten/studienarbeit/badias-2020-morph-dslam/</guid><description>URL: http://arxiv.org/pdf/2009.00576.pdf Video: http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=P_QN8Nv&amp;ndash;_g To read!</description></item><item><title>Cadena 2016 Past, Present, and Future of SLAM</title><link>https://salehahr.github.io/zettelkasten/studienarbeit/cadena-2016/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://salehahr.github.io/zettelkasten/studienarbeit/cadena-2016/</guid><description>Authors Cadena et al
Abstract
cited by 1.2k people &amp;ldquo;This paper simultaneously serves as a position paper and tutorial to those who are users of SLAM&amp;rdquo; Recommended other works s. Works of possible interest Contents/Chapters Takeaway</description></item><item><title>Durrant-Whyte 2006 SLAM Tutorial Part I</title><link>https://salehahr.github.io/zettelkasten/studienarbeit/durrant-whyte-2006-slam-tutorial-part-i/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://salehahr.github.io/zettelkasten/studienarbeit/durrant-whyte-2006-slam-tutorial-part-i/</guid><description>Backlinks: Works of possible interest Authors: Bailey, Durrant-Whyte
Abstract:
Contents/Chapters
Takeaway</description></item><item><title>Chen 2018 SLAM-based dense surface reconstruction in MIS with AR</title><link>https://salehahr.github.io/zettelkasten/studienarbeit/chen-2018-mis-slam/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://salehahr.github.io/zettelkasten/studienarbeit/chen-2018-mis-slam/</guid><description>Authors Chen et al
Abstract
Intra-operative dense surface reconstruction framework to provide geometry information from only monocular videos The proposed framework works well with rapid camera movements, however is not suitable for large deformations Only tweaks ORBSLAM to adjust between point density and computational performance Contents/Chapters Problems in medical AR:
tissue surface illumination tissue deformation rapid movements of the medical tool e.g. endoscope (s. also kidnapped robot problem for relocalisation, tracking mus therefore be robust) field of view often very small &amp;ldquo;A typical human uses 14 visual cues to perceive depth, only 3/14 are binocular vision related.</description></item><item><title>Works of possible interest</title><link>https://salehahr.github.io/zettelkasten/bibliography/works-of-interest/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://salehahr.github.io/zettelkasten/bibliography/works-of-interest/</guid><description>General SLAM Cadena 2016 &amp;ndash; Past, Present, and Future of SLAM durrant-whyte 2006 slam tutorial part i Prerequisites g2o paper - graph-based SLAM Existing SLAM algorithms MonoSLAM, works by Andrew Davison focusing on fusion instead of vision-only SLAM
Maplab (filtering-based) not looking at filtering-based algos
mentioned in the Chen 2018 Review of VI SLAM paper:
ORB-SLAM paper — ORB features VIORB implementation ORB-SLAM3 (improves on ORBSLAM, incl.</description></item><item><title>Wikipedia SLAM</title><link>https://salehahr.github.io/zettelkasten/studienarbeit/wikipedia-slam/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://salehahr.github.io/zettelkasten/studienarbeit/wikipedia-slam/</guid><description>Source: http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Simultaneous_localization_and_mapping Parents: SLAM Index , slam-resources Different types of sensors give rise to different SLAM algorithms whose assumptions are most appropriate to the sensors.
At one extreme, visual features provide details of many points within an area &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; rendering SLAM unnecessary shapes in these point clouds can be easily and unambiguously aligned at each step via image registration . At the opposite extreme, tactile sensors are extremely sparse they contain only information about points very close to the agent require strong prior models to compensate in purely tactile SLAM.</description></item></channel></rss>