<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>-published on Zettelkasten</title><link>https://salehahr.github.io/zettelkasten/tags/published/</link><description>Recent content in -published on Zettelkasten</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-uk</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://salehahr.github.io/zettelkasten/tags/published/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>(Science Focus) How can one eye alone provide depth perception</title><link>https://salehahr.github.io/zettelkasten/bibliography/science-focus/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://salehahr.github.io/zettelkasten/bibliography/science-focus/</guid><description>Source: http://www.sciencefocus.com/the-human-body/how-can-one-eye-alone-provide-depth-perception/
Author: Hilary Guite
In humans with normal binocular vision, depth perception is obtained using the parallax in the two overlapping fields of vision (&amp;ldquo;binocular disparity&amp;rdquo;)
Each single field of vision has a slightly different view to the other If vision in one eye is impaired, depth perception is still obtainable even with only one eye. Some tricks that the brain uses:
We know the real size of things Using perspective, e.</description></item><item><title>Monocular depth perception</title><link>https://salehahr.github.io/zettelkasten/permanent/10-monocular-depth-perception/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://salehahr.github.io/zettelkasten/permanent/10-monocular-depth-perception/</guid><description>Depth perception in real life In nature, prey animals typically have eyes on either side of their head to maximise field of view, while most predators have forward-facing eyes with overlapping fields of vision (binocular vision) for maximum depth perception. Humans also have binocular vision. (Some exceptions: fruit bats, killer whales)
We perceive depth, or distance to the objects that we see, based on several visual cues.</description></item><item><title>Parallax</title><link>https://salehahr.github.io/zettelkasten/definitions/parallax/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://salehahr.github.io/zettelkasten/definitions/parallax/</guid><description>Source: https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Parallax
Definition: The difference in the apparent position of an object viewed from two different positions
This difference is given by the angle between the two lines of sight Binocular vision uses parallax in the overlapping fields of vision in order to gain depth perception Distance measurement (i.e. depth from the viewer) via parallax is based on the principle of triangulation (uses trigonometry, s. Monocular depth perception in humans )</description></item></channel></rss>